<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Setup on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Setup on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install/</guid><description>System requirements Project OutFox has builds for Windows, macOS, and Linux. We also have specific builds for ARM-based Linux devices and Apple M1-based computers. It should run on just about any computer from the mid-2000s onward, depending on the operating system and hardware specifications. We have had alphas running on CPUs as old as the Pentium E2180.
The Windows build of Project OutFox requires Windows 7 or later.</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/getting-started/</guid><description>To obtain the best experience, there are a few things you should do after installing Project OutFox. Some of these instructions assume usage of the included default theme (Soundwaves).
Selecting a game type When launching Project OutFox for the first time or without save data present, you will be prompted to select which game type you would like to begin with. Project OutFox supports a variety of game types, which you can learn about here, which simulate different types of rhythm games (including button layouts and, where applicable, gameplay behaviours specific to the game type).</description></item><item><title>Configure controllers</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/controllers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/controllers/</guid><description>On Alpha 4.5 and newer, we switched to using an XInput-compliant input system.
Due to these changes, not all controllers (such as gamepads, dance pads, and other rhythm game-specific controllers) are guaranteed to function with 5.3 out of the box (even if they were supported on earlier versions), unless a controller mapping profile has been created for that specific controller.
We would like to thank Josen Tiamat for writing these new instructions for how to configure your controllers for use on 5.</description></item></channel></rss>