<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Setup on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Setup on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install/</guid><description>System requirements Project OutFox has builds for Windows, macOS, and Linux. We also have specific builds for ARM-based Linux devices and Apple M1-based computers. It should run on just about any computer from the mid-2000s onward, depending on the operating system and hardware specifications. We have had alphas running on CPUs as old as the Pentium E2180.
The Windows build of Project OutFox requires Windows 7 or later. Windows XP builds are available for selected releases, which require Service Pack 3.</description></item><item><title>Installation on Linux &amp; Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-linux/</guid><description>Important note Determining what version to download Installing the game Portable vs Non-portable mode Running the game Extra NoteSkins Common problems Missing libraries Audio not playing / going to the wrong device Needing to force ALSA instead of PulseAudio. Needing to force a different audio driver Arcade Machine Conversion With Pi LITBoard/Arduino Instructions Important note Do not extract or run the game as the root user. It&amp;rsquo;s considered very unsafe, and you will have permission issues.</description></item><item><title>Installation on Mac OS</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-mac/</guid><description>Note to users using &amp;ldquo;App Store Only Applications&amp;rdquo; Using this permission will make Gatekeeper revoke necessary permissions that Project OutFox needs to read the game content (Given the app loads files externally). So, if you are using this option instead of &amp;ldquo;App Store and Identified Developers&amp;rdquo;, change it before downloading the software.
This option can be found on System Preferences -&amp;gt; Security and Privacy -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Allow apps downloaded from:&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Installation on Windows</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/install-windows/</guid><description>Windows builds of Project OutFox use an installer; follow the instructions, and launch the game using the provided shortcuts.
It is recommended that you do not install it to the Program Files directory, as this is known to cause problems. The installer offers optional components, such as the noteskins that were included with StepMania 5.0.12 and 5.1, and &amp;ldquo;Toasties&amp;rdquo; - animations that can trigger on combo milestones in-game. By default, the game is installed in &amp;ldquo;Portable Mode&amp;rdquo;; save data is stored in the installation directory.</description></item><item><title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/key_shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/key_shortcuts/</guid><description>Project OutFox has quite a few keyboard shortcuts to make certain tasks easier.
Global Shortcuts These shortcuts work everywhere in OutFox unless otherwise specified (or used in another section).
F1: Insert Coin
F2: Reload metrics, textures, noteskins &amp;amp; code detector cache (Does nothing in edit mode)
Ctrl+F2: Reload theme scripts (Does nothing in edit mode)
Shift+F2: Reload metrics, noteskins &amp;amp; code detector cache (Does nothing in edit mode)
Ctrl+Shift+F2: Reload overlay screens &amp;amp; metrics (Does nothing in edit mode)</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/getting-started/</guid><description>To obtain the best experience, there are a few things you should do after installing Project OutFox. Some of these instructions assume usage of the included default theme (Soundwaves).
Selecting a game type When launching Project OutFox for the first time or without save data present, you will be prompted to select which game type you would like to begin with. Project OutFox supports a variety of game types, which you can learn about here, which simulate different types of rhythm games (including button layouts and, where applicable, gameplay behaviours specific to the game type).</description></item><item><title>Configure controllers</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/controllers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/setup/controllers/</guid><description>On Alpha 4.5 and newer, we switched to using an XInput-compliant input system.
Due to these changes, not all controllers (such as game-pads, dance pads, and other rhythm game-specific controllers) are guaranteed to function with OutFox out of the box (even if they were supported on earlier versions), unless a controller mapping profile has been created for that specific controller.
We would like to thank Josen Tiamat for writing these new instructions for how to configure your controllers for use on OutFox.</description></item></channel></rss>