<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Front Matter on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Front Matter on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Project OutFox</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/about/</guid><description>What is Project OutFox? Project OutFox is a fork of StepMania 5.1. The project began to improve the main repo and it&amp;rsquo;s codebase, however due to community feedback and response the project changed direction into what it is today; A working museum of scrolling rhythm games playable within a single client.
The team provides a free-to-play cross-platform engine supporting and supported by the many new communities and areas that OutFox now supports.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/faq/</guid><description>This page has some of the more commonly asked questions pitched to us from the community, remember if you cannot find your answer here, feel free to ask in the discord server!
Will OutFox still work with my old songs/themes/etc..? Project OutFox builds upon the existing StepMania 5.0.12/5.1 beta codebase, and maintaining backwards compatibility with older content is one of our main priorities. Content that worked on StepMania 5.0.12/5.1 (including songs, themes, and noteskins) should still work on OutFox.</description></item><item><title>OutFox Serenity</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity/</guid><description>Hey! There are new pages with more info about OutFox Serenity, check them out!
Serenity User Profiles Serenity Volume Resume What is OutFox Serenity? OutFox Serenity is the official community song pack project made primarily for Project OutFox. Its purpose is to produce packs of &amp;ldquo;libre&amp;rdquo; songs for the game that can be freely redistributed (including as part of its default, bundled songs), and to showcase the functionality of Project Outfox by offering charts for multiple game types beyond just 4-key/dance.</description></item><item><title>Serenity User Profile</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity_user_profile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity_user_profile/</guid><description>Select User:
Select an option Tags Resume Select user to view resume.
Most Charted Song: Select User to View.
Most Charted Mode: Select User to View
Socials Song Submissions Graphic Submissions Chart Submission If you want a social add/removed from your profile then join the Project OutFox Discord Server and contact the moderator team.
Want the data that we have stored for this profile? Click the button bellow and the JSON Object will be copied to your clipboard.</description></item><item><title>Serenity Volumes Resume</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity_volume_resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity_volume_resume/</guid><description>This page requires JavaScript to work. Select Volume: Select an option Written and Maintained by Moru Zerinho6</description></item></channel></rss>