<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Front Matter on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Front Matter on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Project OutFox</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/about/</guid><description>What is Project OutFox Project OutFox is a fork of StepMania 5.1, led by a group of veterans and other prominent figures in the community. Its main goals include:
Refactoring its internal codebase to improve performance, adhere to modern coding practices, and enhance its capabilities on modern hardware and other platforms. We have worked on support for single-board ARM systems such as Raspberry Pi), and improvements to uncapped frame rate have also been recorded on hardware as far back as the Pentium E2180.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/faq/</guid><description>What is Project OutFox? A project to modernize the StepMania 5.0.12/5.1 codebase to improve its performance and provide enhanced support for modern hardware and operating systems. We are also adding new features, including those being requested by our community, as well as refurbishing its support of non-dance/4-key game types, adding new game types, and so forth.
Will it still work with my old songs/themes/etc..? Project OutFox builds upon the existing StepMania 5.</description></item><item><title>OutFox Serenity</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/meta/serenity/</guid><description>What is OutFox Serenity? OutFox Serenity is the official community song pack project made primarily for Project OutFox. Its purpose is to produce packs of &amp;ldquo;libre&amp;rdquo; songs for the game that can be freely redistributed (including as part of its default, bundled songs), and to showcase the functionality of Project Outfox by offering charts for multiple game types beyond just 4-key/dance.
How was OutFox Serenity created? During Project OutFox Alpha 4.</description></item></channel></rss>