<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Features &amp; Config on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/</link><description>Recent content in Features &amp; Config on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preferences.ini</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/preferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/preferences/</guid><description>Preferences.ini is a file that contains many of the system preferences. Some of them are accessible within Project OutFox&amp;rsquo;s settings menu, but some of them are only accessible by editing the file. Manual edits to Preferences.ini must be performed when the game is closed, or else they may be automatically overwritten.
It is located in the Save folder.
List of parameters AdditionalCourseFolders Takes a comma-separated list of directories where additional course (.</description></item><item><title>Content folders</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/folders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/config/folders/</guid><description>Project OutFox uses various folders to store content, such as songs, save data, themes, noteskins, etc. Content is stored in one of the three following locations;
Global folders are located within the Project OutFox installation directory. If you are on a multi-user operating system, content in these folders will be accessible to all users. When Portable Mode is enabled by placing a blank file named Portable.ini at the root of the installation directory, save data (including profiles and preference files) will be place in a subfolder of the installation directory named &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>