<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Supported Game Modules on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/</link><description>Recent content in Supported Game Modules on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Module: be-mu</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bemu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bemu/</guid><description>be-mu seven key long note game-play, default legacy theme
be-mu seven key mine game-play, default legacy theme
About History: This mode started life as a notes loader for obscure dance charts created in 1998, with 4 key and 6 key being supported. 4k doubles seemed to appear around 2000, before being replaced completely with MSD/DWI around the same time. The loader has been present for a very long time in the games history, not adding actual BMS support until 2003.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: bongo</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bongo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bongo/</guid><description>About It parses files made for taitai into a lane mode to play on a bongo based controller, or bongo based midi controller. One must hit the left or right bongo drum when it reaches the receptor, or clap your hands when the star appears. Scoring and timing windows are yet to be decided.
History: The parser support for the mode is currently actively developed, and the chart support will be aligned with the taiko simulator based parser support.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: dance</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/dance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/dance/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: This history does not include the original years before the project was announced and given to the community. If you know of any builds or information missing, do let us know! you can find some of these earlier builds at the archive here https://josevarela.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: ds3ddx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ds3ddx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ds3ddx/</guid><description>3ddx single game-play, default legacy theme 3ddx double game-play, default legacy theme About This mode simulates the game play from the Korean game Dance Station 3DDX which was released in the summer of 2000. The machine was designed with 2 dance pads in front of the cabinet which contained 4 depressible areas in the corners, alongside infra-red sensors which the player would need to wave hands over to count as a &amp;lsquo;hit&amp;rsquo; in the up down left right areas of the pad.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: ez2d</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ez2d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ez2d/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: 5 Panel (UpperLeftHand/UpperRightHand/LowerLeftHand/LowerRightHand): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-single) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-double) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-real) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.0 beta 1 - (ez2-single-versus) (8 July 2002) StepMania v3.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gddm</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gddm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gddm/</guid><description>Early GDDM playback, default legacy theme
About History: This mode was added in Project OutFox. It was added to provide users with a 5/9/10 lane drum mode that works on Linux and Mac OS.
When added, players could use the auto-gen system to test it out, and there was noticeable lag on Windows due to the sound drivers. This was resolved in Alpha 4.12, when we rewrote the MIDI input system.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gdgf</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gdgf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gdgf/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in Project OutFox. It started as the &amp;ldquo;guitar&amp;rdquo; mode, before the &amp;ldquo;gh&amp;rdquo; mode existed. Around the time the &amp;ldquo;gh&amp;rdquo; mode came into being, this mode was renamed to &amp;ldquo;gdgf&amp;rdquo;, which is the current name.
This mode is selectable in the game select screen.
Introduced: First Seen:
OutFox Alpha 4.6 RC2 - &amp;quot;Guitar5&amp;quot; (21 June 2020, The game is known as &amp;ldquo;Guitar&amp;rdquo; at this point) OutFox Alpha 4.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gh</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gh/</guid><description>About History: This mode was originally created to simulate a popular game using a guitar shaped controller. It was added in StepMania 4, however work to finish it was not completed. It was rewritten and added back in Project OutFox in Spring 2021.
Introduced (StepMania 4): 5 Key: First Seen:
StepMania v4.0 CVS - (guitar-five) (23 September 2006) (Non-Functional) Removed
StepMania v5.0 preview 2 - (guitar-five) (30 July 2011) (sm-ssc v2.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: karaoke</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/karaoke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/karaoke/</guid><description>This mode will be added in a future release of alpha 5 of Project OutFox. About History: There was a lot of code produced by Chris Danford for this mode back in 2008, that went seemingly completely unused until it&amp;rsquo;s removal 2 years later. OutFox will use more modern techniques that what was written at the time, and we will restore the vision of the engine having a karaoke mode once again.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: kbm</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbm/</guid><description>This mode will be added around alpha 4.19.0/alpha 5.0.0-pre45-ish of Project OutFox. About This mode parses files made in the bmson format, and usually is arranged into a two octave keyboard layout, sporting 24 keys in a piano style layout. This mode also supports 4 octave mode, or 48 keys. It is Highly recommended that this mode is played on a MIDI controller, or if you can find one, an original keyboardmania Playstation 2 controller from the early 2000s</description></item><item><title>Game Module: kbx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbx/</guid><description>kb4 game-play, default legacy theme kb6 game-play, default legacy theme About History: The mode (kb7) was added in StepMania 4 CVS. It was designed to be a keyboard based mode using 7 keys (6 normal keys and the spacebar) and was requested by the community, as an alternative to the dance only focus at the time, with a view of providing keyboard players a better streamlined experience in the engine.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: kickbox</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kickbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kickbox/</guid><description>kb4 game-play, default legacy theme kb6 game-play, default legacy theme About History: This mode was added in StepMania 5. It was designed to be a fitness based punch and kick mode commissioned by a member of the community.
It has always been considered obscure, but it does have a functioning autogen system, and is functional again from Project OutFox 4.10.0.
You need to ensure you click the &amp;lsquo;use SM5 noteskins&amp;rsquo; on the windows installer to allow yourself access to this mode if you are using Project OutFox.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: maniax</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/maniax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/maniax/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in 3.0.2, starting off life as a keyboard mode. There were several styles added later on. The sensors were called either Hand Upper or Hand Lower
Introduced: 4 Sensor (HUL/HUR/HLL/HLR): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0.2 - (single) (3 September 2003) StepMania v3.0.2 - (double) (3 September 2003) Gameplay Play Styles Grading / Accuracy Scoring Health Bar Modding Charting Controls Trivia Written and Maintained with ♡ by Squirrel</description></item><item><title>Game Module: para</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/para/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/para/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: 5 Panel (UpLeft/UpRight/Up/Left/Right): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0 beta 6 - (Para Single) (7th September 2002) StepMania v3.0.2 - (para-versus) (10th July 2004) Project OutFox alpha 4.9.7.3 - (double) (April 4 2021) Replaced by:
StepMania v3.0 beta 6 - (single) (15 September 2002) 8 Panel (UpLeft/UpRight/Up/Left/Right/BackRight/Back/BackLeft): First Seen:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: po-mu</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pomu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pomu/</guid><description>po-mu nine playback, bun noteskin, default legacy theme
About History: This mode was added in version 3.0.2. There was no support for the associated loaders at this time, nor any theme or scoring updates. Po-mu was rendered accidentally broken during the CVS era of development on StepMania 4 (January 2007), where it was not restored until Project OutFox Alpha 4.9.8 (25th April 2021) with a new notesloader and rewritten internal code.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: pump</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pump/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from very early on in the 3.0 development cycle. Since then, it has benefitted from having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years. In the SSC era of development, pump was actually set as the default (main) game mode for a while, but it has since moved to the second on the game select option. There have been several forks and adaptations of this mode since the sm-ssc 1.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: rb</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/rb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/rb/</guid><description>About History: This mode supports the drum layouts added to the console guitar games of the late 2000s. Following support that was added for the guitar modes back in 2004 it was possible that support for drums was a potential option in the future, although looking within the codebase we have been unable to find any evidence the mode was planned.
This mode was heavily requested after full midi notes loader support was added for the gh mode, and as of writing only midi charts with drums will load in Outfox.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: smx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/smx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/smx/</guid><description>smx songs in music wheel, default theme smx game-play, default legacy theme About: History: This mode was re-added towards the end of the alpha 4 development cycle of Project OutFox at the end of 2021. It is a simulation of the game StepManiaX by StepRevolution, and was created with their blessing. It began life on our original base development back in 2018, when the project was codenamed FoxMania.
Introduced (FoxMania): 5 Sensor (L/U/C/R/D): First Seen:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: stepstage</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/stepstage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/stepstage/</guid><description>stepstage game-play, default legacy theme About: History: This mode was added towards the end of the alpha 4 development cycle of Project OutFox at the beginning of 2022. It is a simulation of the game Stepping Stage by Jaleco, released in 2000, featuring 6 panels on 2 columns, with a top middle and bottom pad layout in a hexagon.
Introduced: 6 Panel (LTRed/LMBlue/LLYellow/RTRed/RMBlue/RLYellow): First Seen:
Project OutFox alpha 4.13.0 - (single) (28 January 2022) Project OutFox alpha 4.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: taitai</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/taiko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/taiko/</guid><description>About History: This mode was re-added in alpha 4.9.9HF of Project OutFox. In its&amp;rsquo; original form, it was a five-column mode with each note type having its&amp;rsquo; own column. Later, within the same alpha (July 11 2021), it was redone to have the notes be different note types instead of notes in columns, with only one column being needed.
In this mode the parser support for the mode is being actively developed, and the chart support will be aligned with other taiko based simulators to provide parity and coherence for the community.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: techno</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/techno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/techno/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in the 3.0.2, with the first mode being 8 panel. Like most modes from this period, there were not many theme items or specifics in scoring or timing windows at all. It was rendered almost unplayable due to the rapid code changes of the time, and was fixed in the side fork of 3.9.5 around spring 2004.
In the development of SM 4.0, this mode was broken with the rapid changes brought into the game and was then fixed again by Team SSC in StepMania 5 Preview 4 aroun 2010, restoring doubles and noteskin support.</description></item></channel></rss>