<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Supported Game Modules on Project OutFox Wiki</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/</link><description>Recent content in Supported Game Modules on Project OutFox Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Module: be-mu</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bemu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/bemu/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in the 3.0 beta era, starting off life as a simple mode with no keysounds or even using the correct keys. The familiar 7K setup we know and love was added later in 2005.
The mode did not see much use and fell into having a broken notesloader around the summer of 2010, making it not work with older BMS files, or files with BME or BML extensions.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: dance</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/dance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/dance/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: 4 Panel (Up/Down/Left/Right): First Seen:
StepMania 0.93 - (single4) (17th October 2001) StepMania 0.94 - (versus4) (20 November 2001) StepMania 0.94 - (double4) (20 November 2001) StepMania 1.64 - (couple) (19 March 2002) StepMania v3.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: ds3ddx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ds3ddx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ds3ddx/</guid><description>About History: Introduced: 4 Panel 4 Sensor: First Seen:
StepMania v3.0 final - (single) (28th December 2002) Project OutFox alpha 4.13.0 - (double) (31 January 2022) Project OutFox alpha 4.13.0 - (versus) (31 January 2022) Gameplay Play Styles Grading / Accuracy Scoring Health Bar Modding Charting Controls Trivia</description></item><item><title>Game Module: ez2d</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ez2d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/ez2d/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: 5 Panel (UpperLeftHand/UpperRightHand/LowerLeftHand/LowerRightHand): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-single) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-double) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.0 &amp;ldquo;compatibility test&amp;rdquo; - (ez2-real) (20 June 2002) StepMania v3.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gddm</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gddm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gddm/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in Project OutFox. It was added to provide users with a 5/9/10 lane drum mode that works on linux and Mac OS.
When added, players could use the auto-gen system to test it out, and there is noticeable lag on windows due to the sound drivers. This will be resolved in a future release.
This mode is selectable in the game select screen.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gdgf</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gdgf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gdgf/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in Project OutFox. It started as the &amp;ldquo;guitar&amp;rdquo; mode, before the &amp;ldquo;gh&amp;rdquo; mode existed. Around the time the &amp;ldquo;gh&amp;rdquo; mode came into being, this mode was renamed to &amp;ldquo;gdgf&amp;rdquo;, which is the current name.
This mode is selectable in the game select screen.
Introduced: First Seen:
OutFox Alpha 4.6 RC2 - &amp;quot;Guitar5&amp;quot; (21 June 2020, The game is known as &amp;ldquo;Guitar&amp;rdquo; at this point) OutFox Alpha 4.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: gh</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/gh/</guid><description>About History: This mode was originally created to simulate a popular game using a guitar shaped controller. It was added in StepMania 4, however work to finish it was not completed. It was rewritten and added back in Project OutFox in Spring 2021.
Introduced (StepMania 4): 5 Key: First Seen:
StepMania v4.0 CVS - (guitar-five) (23 September 2006) (Non-Functional) Removed</description></item><item><title>Game Module: kbx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kbx/</guid><description>kb4 game-play, default legacy theme kb6 game-play, default legacy theme About History: This mode (kb7) was added in StepMania 4 CVS. It was designed to be a keyboard based mode using 7 keys and was requested by the community, as an alternative to the dance only focus at the time, with a view of providing keyboard players a better streamlined experience in the engine.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: kickbox</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kickbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/kickbox/</guid><description>kb4 game-play, default legacy theme kb6 game-play, default legacy theme About History: This mode was added in StepMania 5. It was designed to be a fitness based punch and kick mode commissioned by a member of the community.
It has always been considered obscure, but it does have a functioning autogen system, and is functional again in Project OutFox 4.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: maniax</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/maniax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/maniax/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in 3.0.2, starting off life as a keyboard mode. There were several styles added later on. The sensors were called either Hand Upper or Hand Lower
Introduced: 4 Sensor (HUL/HUR/HLL/HLR): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0.2 - (single) (3 September 2003) StepMania v3.0.2 - (double) (3 September 2003) Gameplay Play Styles Grading / Accuracy Scoring Health Bar Modding Charting Controls Trivia</description></item><item><title>Game Module: para</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/para/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/para/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from the very beginning of the history of the StepMania project, having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years.
Introduced: 5 Panel (UpLeft/UpRight/Up/Left/Right): First Seen:
StepMania v3.0 beta 6 - (Para Single) (7th September 2002) StepMania v3.0.2 - (para-versus) (10th July 2004) Project OutFox alpha 4.9.7.3 - (double) (April 4 2021) Replaced by:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: po-mu</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pomu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pomu/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in version 3.0.2. There was no support for the associated loaders at this time, nor any theme or scoring updates. Po-mu was rendered accidentally broken during the CVS era of development on StepMania 4 (January 2007), where it was not restored until Project OutFox Alpha 4.9.8 (25th April 2021) with a new notesloader and rewritten internal code.
Introduced: 3 Key (LW/LY/LG): First Seen:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: pump</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/pump/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added from very early on in the 3.0 development cycle. Since then, it has benefitted from having several different tweaks and fixes done throughout the years. In the SSC era of development, pump was actually set as the default (main) game mode for a while, but it has since moved to the second on the game select option. There have been several forks and adaptations of this mode since the sm-ssc 1.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: smx</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/smx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/smx/</guid><description>smx songs in music wheel, default theme smx game-play, default legacy theme About: History: This mode was added towards the end of the alpha 4 development cycle of Project OutFox at the end of 2021. It is a simulation of the game StepManiaX by StepRevolution, and was created with their blessing.
Introduced: 5 Sensor (L/U/C/R/D): First Seen:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: stepstage</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/stepstage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/stepstage/</guid><description>stepstage game-play, default legacy theme About: History: This mode was added towards the end of the alpha 4 development cycle of Project OutFox at the beginning of 2022. It is a simulation of the game Stepping Stage by Jaleco, released in 2000, featuring 6 panels on 2 columns, with a top middle and bottom pad layout in a hexagon.
Introduced: 6 Panel (LTRed/LMBlue/LLYellow/RTRed/RMBlue/RLYellow): First Seen:</description></item><item><title>Game Module: taiko</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/taiko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/taiko/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in alpha 4.9.9HF of Project OutFox. In its' original form, it was a five-column mode with each note type having its' own column. Later, within the same alpha (July 11 2021), it was redone to have the notes be different note types instead of notes in columns, with only one column being needed.
Right now, this mode can only be played with auto-gen charts.</description></item><item><title>Game Module: techno</title><link>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/techno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://outfox.wiki/user-guide/games/techno/</guid><description>About History: This mode was added in the 3.0.2, with the first mode being 8 panel. Like most modes from this period, there were not many theme items or specifics in scoring or timing windows at all.
In the development of SM 4.0, this mode was broken with the rapid changes brought into the game and was then fixed again by Team SSC in StepMania 5 Preview 4, restoring doubles and noteskin support.</description></item></channel></rss>